Nicolas Vycas Nery

FullStack Developer | Python | SQL | Java | Typescript

Rio de Janeiro - Brazil

Summary

I'm Nicolas, a programmer with 8 years of studies in the field. I began studying software development in 2016 while attending FAETEC's technical high school, where I focused on Java development. Since then, I've continued to build my skills and knowledge through self-study and my current studies in Computer Science at CEFET/RJ.

I'm particularly interested in fullstack development because I enjoy being involved in all aspects of a project, from the front-end to the back-end. For me, it's all about finding the best solution to the problem at hand, regardless of the technology stack or business domain.

Currently, I'm an intern at TCU,Federal Court of Accounts, in the Data Scientist area, where I work with Python, PowerBI, SQL, and other technologies. My goal is to transition into a software development role, which was my original career objective 8 years ago.

In addition to my work at TCU, I was working part-time full stack developer at BetaBit, where I work with React, NestJS, NodeJS, Typescript, PostgreSQL, AWS, and other technologies.

Contact

+55(21)985924834 vycasnicolas@gmail.com

Education Higher Education

In progress

(Bachelor's degree in Computer Science) at CEFET/RJ

Federal Center for Technological Education (2020 – 2024)

Technical High School

Completed

(Technical education in informatics) at FAETEC

State Technical School República (2016 - 2018)

Experiences

Tribunal de Contas da União Internship

Data Science Internship Python | Pandas | Matplotlib | Seaborn | Numpy | Excel

Data mining and management of structured data, using Microsoft Excel, Power Bi and Python. Assistance in the creation of Python programs / script using the following tools / technologies:

Jupyter, pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, numpy, SQL, Excel

Aug 2021 - Present · 1 yr 10 mos





Nicolas Vycas Nery

FullStack Developer | Python | SQL | Java | Typescript Rio de Janeiro - Brazil

Cefet/RJ - Centro Federal de Educação Tecnológica Celso Suckow da Fonseca

Undergraduate Researcher, Unity | Python | C# Assisting in the creation of a game with a focus on interface for visually impaired individuals using the following technologies: Unity, Python, and C#.

Nov 2022 - Present · 7 mos

BetaBit Dev · Part-time

Full Stack Software Developer TypeScript | ReactJs | NextJs | NestJs

As a part-time Full Stack Software Developer, I was responsible for developing web applications using the latest technologies, following agile methodology.

On the frontend, I used React, Next.js, and Tailwind Css to create rich and intuitive interfaces, making web applications more attractive and user-friendly.

On the backend, I used Nest.js, TypeORM, and PostgreSQL to create scalable and robust web applications. I also use Python and FastAPI to create RESTful APIs.

Additionally, I use tools such as Git to version my code and Docker to create isolated development and production environments.

Summary the Technologies used:

React, Next.js, Tailwind Css, Nest.js, TypeORM, Python, FastAPI, PostgreSQL, Git, Docker, Agile, Firebase

Volunteering Work

Class Assistant - Data Structures Course C++ | C

- I assisted the class in addressing student's doubts in the course. I use the C and C++ languages and provide assistance with the development of the following topics:
- Sequential linear structures
- Sorting algorithms
- Heterogeneous composite variables
- Pointers
- Dynamic linear structures
- Non-linear data structures Trees

Mar 2022 - Oct 2022 · 8 mos

Languages

- Portuguese Native
- English Fluent



